# Ahmed Abduljabar

#### Senior Network Engineer

Hayward, CA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Ahmed-Abduljabar/08b4cf2568d54709

Twelve years of extensive hands-on experience in network engineering, windows system administration, troubleshooting and repair. Designed, installed, configured and maintained complex routed LAN and WAN networks. Excellent communication skills with the ability to interface at all levels. A team player who also can work well independently.

#### ~ Selected Skills & Competencies ~

Broad understanding of all aspects of LAN and WAN operations, including load balancing, routing, IP assignment, and standard networking protocols.

Hands-on experience with TCP/IP, OSI, Cisco routers and switches, routing protocols and firewalls.

Solid execution of network analysis and configuration, in addition to managing Windows, MAC OS, Linux, MS-Office, VMware, Observium and most important Wireshark.

Awareness of basic security threat mitigation, protecting networks through password encryptions, VPN tunneling, and more.

Part of the Protocols that I am experienced with it:

Routing Protocols:(IGP): RIP, OSPF, ISIS and EIGRP. (EGP): BGP.

First-Hop Redundancy Protocols: HSRP, VRRP, GLBP.

Others: TCP/IP, GRE & IPsec Tunnels, NAT, AAA, STP, RSTP, MST, Redistribution, DNS, DHCP, TFTP,

MPLS, ACLs, VPN, QoS, DMVPN, CDP, DDR .. etc.

Hardware:

Cisco routers: 800, 1800, 1900, 2800, 2900, 3800, 3900, 4000 series.

Cisco switches: 2960, 3560, 3650, 3750, 3850, 4500, 6500 series.

Cisco firewalls: ASA 5505, ASA 5510, ASA 5585-X.

Cisco industrial switches: 1000, 2000U, 2000, 3000, 3010, 4000, 4010, 5000, 2500 series. Other Vendors: Brocade layer 2/3 switches, Moxa Layer 2/3 switches, HP, HPE and Dell.

Willing to relocate to: San Francisco Bay Area, CA - Los Angeles, CA - I prefer within California but willing

to consider other opportunities

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Network Engineer**

HSQ Technology - Hayward, CA - February 2014 to Present

Design, install, configure and maintain the LAN/WAN networks for our customers, Creating the required documents/drawings and Implemented solutions for the enterprise networks to meet their requirements, Our customers networks have a wide diversity of network equipments from different vendors with the main being Cisco, Brocade, Moxa and HP.

## ~ Project Highlights ~

Designed and Implemented network solution for the customers based on the project specifications.

Creating the PDR/FDR documents/drawings for the network.

Write/Perform the FAT/FIT/FST test procedure.

Integrate the new network with the existing/old system and ensure smooth transition.

Review and enhance network security using best practices and industry standards.

Provide support for existing and old projects as well as design the upgrade/expanding plan for their network. I have completed more than 20 project of different sizes with HSQ Technology.

### **Network Engineer**

Kufan-Group - Baghdad - March 2009 to July 2013

Primary specialist for a major e-government project involving a complex architecture connecting local ministries into one wireless broadband network, Coordinate all product installations, transmissions, and configurations alongside other technical functions that assure complete integrity and security of the infrastructure.

#### ~ Project Highlights ~

Administer all necessary devices at more than 40 ministries and government sites using Microwave Multipoint Technology and point-to-point Ericsson products; install Cisco routers, switches, firewalls, and Cambridge wireless products.

Ensure consistent levels of network capabilities by conducting test plans to evaluate infrastructure performance as well as calculating bandwidth/performance using iPerf3 among other software.

Provide High level of security to the network by setting Cisco Firewall ASA5510 in each site.

Serve as Call Manager, configuring IP phone systems and other communication tools as needed, while facilitating a solid operational workflow.

#### Junior Network Engineer

Several Small Companies - Baghdad - August 2005 to March 2009

Over the period of 4 years while I was a college student, I worked for several small companies as Junior Network Engineer / Help Desk Support .. installed, configured and maintained the LAN network, repaired and maintained the Workstations/Servers. During the summer break I would take a full time job and part time jobs for the rest of the year, One summer break I get the chance to work for 3 companies at the same time, dividing my time between them 6:00AM - 10:00PM .. it was a great experience.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **B.Sc. in Computer Tech. Engineer**

DIJLAH UNIVERSITY - Baghdad 2006 to 2010

#### **CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES**

# **Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)**

January 2014 to January 2017

# Cisco Certified Network Professional (CCNP)

January 2014 to January 2017

### Cisco Certified Design Professional (CCDP)

November 2016 to November 2019

#### Cisco Certified Design Associate (CCDA)

September 2016 to September 2019

# **CCNA Security**

August 2015 to August 2018

#### **Brocade Certified Network Engineer (BCNE)**

June 2014 to Present

# **Cisco Certified Network Fundamental (CCNA 1)**

2009 to 2012